

### **ABOUT**

Experienced Full - Stack developer with a background in Uki Technology School, specializing in e-commerce projects, including Windows applications, web sites & databases to ensureseamless user experience. Also, skilled freelancer in UI design, SEO, and Digital Marketing

### CONTACT

- rkkumaran834@gmail.com
- © +94767710834
- Medium/kumaran
- 🛱 Github/kumaran
- Linkedin/kumaran
- Portfolio/kumaran

### **TOP SKILLS**

Hard Skills

HTML, CSS, bootstrap Javascript , ReactJS GitHub, Canva MongoDB , NodeJS ExpressJS , WordPress

Soft Skills
 Management Skills
 Creativity
 Team work
 Critical Thinking
 Leadership/ Planning

#### **PARTICIPATIONS**

- Yarl Geek Challenge (YGC)
   Innovation Festival 2023
   Project Name: VD-Wear
- Volunteer at YarlIT Hub (YGC)
- UI/UX Workshop at YarlIT Hub

## KANTHASUWAMY KUMARAN

### **EXPERIENCES**

Sproutgigs | Freelancer
 2022 - 2023
 Digitel Marking , Designs

Nalin Information
 Technologies (Pvt)Ltd
 2021 - 2022
 System Administrator & Technician

# SDS Computers Jan - August 2023 Hardware & Network Technician

### **PROJECTS**

- VD-Wear
   Virtual-Fitting-Room Web
   Application useing Three.JS
- Todo App
   HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
   MongoDB, Node.js powered.
- Movie Search HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Music App
   Dynamic music app: HTML, CSS, JavaScript for seamless tunes
- Coffee Shop Web
   Created using Google Sites platform
- Calculator HTML, CSS, JavaScript

### **EDUCATIONS**

- College of Technology
   Diploma in ICT
   2021 Present (Part time)
- Vocational Training
   <u>Authority</u>
   Computer Hardware & Network
   NVQ-4
   2020-2021
- J/Anai Balasupramaniya vidiyalaya
   G.C.E. (O/L) Examination
   2001-2015 (B 4C 3S)
   Maths B , ICT - C , Engilsh - C
- <u>Uki Technology School</u>
   Coding Accelerator Program
   2023-2024
- J/Manipay Hindu College G.C.E.(Advanced Level) Examination 2016-2019 C2S BioTech-C, ICT-S, SFT-S

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- FreeCodeCamp
   Responsive Web Design,
   JavaScript Algorithms and
   Data Structures, Front End
   Development Libraries
- Visme
   Creating Memorable Visual

   Presentations
- American Corner
   Web design using HTML, CSS,
   Bootstrap
- Aide et Action
   Computer Graphics Designing
   Photoshop , Canva

MongoDB University

M001: MongoDB Basics M121: The MongoDB Aggregation Framework M320: Data Modeling

- Hacker Rank CSS
   Enhance CSS skills & challenges
   and tutorials online
- Cisco Academy
   <u>Cybersecurity</u>, <u>Internet of Things</u>,
   <u>Linux Essentials</u>, <u>Get Connected</u>
- Startup Essentials Course Yarl Geek Challenge Innovation Festival (VD-Wear)

### **REFERENCES**

M Minerva Jeyarajah
 Lead Lecturer (BIT)
 Head of Uki
 Uki Technology School
 info@uki.life

Vinayagamoorthy Balalojanan
Software Engineering (B.Tech)
Visiting Lecturer
University College Jaffna
janan1992@gmail.com